<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aravindh.net</title>
    <link>https://aravindh.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aravindh.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 14:56:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aravindh.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Coffee table</title>
      <link>https://aravindh.net/post/coffeetable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 14:56:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aravindh.net/post/coffeetable/</guid>
      <description>p {text-indent: 8%;}  Goal and inspiration  Ever since I watched this Youtube video I knew that I was smitten by its design and that I would build one almost exactly like that for my home. I loved the grain directions in the different parts of the legs.   My goal was to build one with specifications that fit my apartment, and to build a gorgeous table top that exhibits natural wood grain and smoothly finished at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFS server based on CentOS 7</title>
      <link>https://aravindh.net/post/nfs_server_centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 12:12:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aravindh.net/post/nfs_server_centos/</guid>
      <description>p {text-indent: 8%;} 
NFS Network File System(NFS) is a widely used distributed filesystem that works reasonably well in most scenarios where you must share a filesytem across several computers. It can use UDP or TCP underneath for transport, and is ofcourse very much configurable to get the best out of it for specific usecases.
At our research cluster, we use NFS for making user&amp;rsquo;s home directories and research datasets available on all compute nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFS performance</title>
      <link>https://aravindh.net/post/zfs_performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 17:55:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aravindh.net/post/zfs_performance/</guid>
      <description>Context This is NOT an all-in post about ZFS performance. I built a FreeBSD+ZFS file server recently at work to serve as an offsite backup server. I wanted to run a few synthetic workloads on it and look at how it fares from performance perspective. Mostly for curiosity and learning purposes.
Performance As stated in the notes about building this server, performance was not one of the priorities, as this server will never face our active workload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFS file server</title>
      <link>https://aravindh.net/post/zfs_fileserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 17:55:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aravindh.net/post/zfs_fileserver/</guid>
      <description>p {text-indent: 8%;}  What is the need? At work, we run a compute cluster that uses an Isilon cluster as primary NAS storage. Excluding snapshots, we have about 200TB of research data, some of them in compressed formats, and others not. We needed an offsite backup file server that would constantly mirror our primary NAS and serve as a quick recovery source in case of a data loss in the the primary NAS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean &amp; fast self-hosted blog</title>
      <link>https://aravindh.net/post/lean_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 17:55:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aravindh.net/post/lean_blog/</guid>
      <description>p {text-indent: 8%;} 
Internet obesity Many websites we routinely visit are just too fat, loading huge amounts of data in the form of javascript files, unoptimized images, web fonts, ads etc. This is just plain inefficient. Take a look of a few sites that I recently visited&amp;hellip;  Source: My tests using online tool at https://tools.pingdom.com/
Why self host? Why not? It&amp;rsquo;s fun.
Say no to walled gardens and own the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>